dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Targeted Tailed Beast
(ガイ)風の国名物の大砂嵐か。
So this is the legendary sandstorm
of the Land of Wind!
(ガイ)噂には聞いていたが
すごいもんだな。
I'd heard rumors,
but this is mind-blowing!
(紅)二次試験を止めたのは正解ね。
Postponing the Second Exam
was wise.
(アスマ)ああ うかつに動けば死ぬ。
Yes, one careless move
and you're dead.
木ノ葉隠れの方々か。
Are you from the Hidden Leaf?
火影から風影様への書状を
預かっている。
We have a letter from Lady Hokage
to Lord Kazekage.
緊急の用件だ。
It's very urgent.
我々が届ける。
We'll deliver it to him.
風影様に 直接お渡しするように
と言われている。
Our instructions are
to deliver it to him in person.
通してもらえませんか？
Will you please let us through?
ならん。
No.
The Second Exam is under
the Sand's jurisdiction.
二次試験は
砂隠れに任されているはず。
それは困った。
That's unfortunate.
でも 通してくれないのなら
木ノ葉に戻るとするか。
Well, since they won't let us through,
should we return to the Leaf Village?
ああ… そうだな。
Yeah, I guess we should.
《２人とも下手な芝居を》
That's really bad acting, you two.
じゃ 失敬！
なに!?
Well, so long!
What?!
逃がすな！
Don't let them get away!
うっ… もう ダメだ…。
I can't take it anymore!
しっかりしろ！
砂漠のチリになるつもりか!?
Hang in there!
Do you want to rot in the desert?!
しかし…。
But...
うわっ!!
(カンクロウ)うろたえんじゃねえ！
Don't get flustered!
(カンクロウ)俺は砂隠れの監督官
カンクロウだ。
I'm Kankuro,
a Hidden Sand proctor.
お前たちを救出にきた。
I'm going to get you out of here.
カンクロウ様が わざわざ
助けにきてくださるとは…。
You came personally
to rescue us, Sir Kankuro?!
俺についてこい。
シェルターまで連れていってやる。
Follow me!
I'll take to you the shelter.
(みんな)はい！
– Yes, sir!
もうダメ… 歩けない。
I can't walk... any further.
えっ？
(テマリ)いいか？ これも
中忍試験だと思って乗り越えろ。
Listen to me!
Think of this as part of
the Second Exam and get through it!
監督官様！
Lady Proctor!
これくらいの砂嵐で
音を上げていたら→
If you end up whining
over a mere sandstorm,
砂隠れの里じゃ
中忍なんかになれやしないぞ！
you'll never make it
as a Sand chunin!
聞きしに勝るとは このことか。
Talk about exceeding
one's expectations...
大砂嵐が これほどのものとは…。
I've never seen
a sandstorm this massive.
息をするのもやっとね。
I can barely breathe...
任せなさい。 俺が止めてやる。
Leave it to me! I'll stop it.
第三生門 開！
Third Gate, Gate of Life... Open!
さぁ ついてこい！
All right, follow me!
うむ 行こう。
ええ。
Okay, let's go.
Yes.
(テンテン)ちょっと… 動かないでよ。
(リー)すみません。
Hey, stop moving around!
Sorry! But staying still is so stifling...
でも じっとしていると
息が詰まりそうで…。
このまま砂に埋もれてしまうなら
いっそ表に飛び出したほうが…。
Instead of getting buried
by the sand like this,
maybe we should make
a run for it...
(ネジ)待て。
Wait...
白眼！
Byakugan!
抜けた！
I broke through!
あと小一時間もすれば
砂嵐はおさまる。
The sandstorm should subside
in about an hour.
動くのは それからだ。
That's when we'll move.
わかりました。
I understand.
あと少しの辛抱ですね。
We just have to endure
a little bit more.
風影様に現状報告を。
I have a report on the situation
for Lord Kazekage.
よし 通れ。
You may enter.
入ります。
Excuse me, my lord.
各班より
砂嵐対策の報告が入っています。
We've received status reports
on the sandstorm from the teams.
現在 受験者たちは ほぼ全員→
Nearly all exam participants have
been evacuated to the shelter.
シェルターに避難していると
思われます。
ん？ 風影様？
Lord Kazekage?
何だ これは!?
What is this?!
どうした!?
What's wrong?!
お前たちの目は節穴か！
Are you men blind?!
砂分身…。
A-A Sand Clone!
風影様は どこにおられる！
Where is Lord Kazekage?!
(マツリ)ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much!
(我愛羅)
礼を言うなら 滝隠れのフウに。
If you thank anyone,
it should be Fuu of
the Hidden Waterfall...
(マツリたち)はい。
行け。
– Y-Yes!
Now go!
二次試験も
じき再開されるだろう。
The Second Exam will
probably resume shortly.
(マツリ)はい。
Y-Yes!
♪♪(琵琶)
(ミコシ)何？
What?!
(ユカタ)敵？
An enemy?!
いったいどこから？
Where's it coming from...?
(ミコシ)コース選択を失敗したようです。
We chose the wrong route.
ここからでは
高台の様子がわかりませんね。
We can't see what's happening
on higher ground from here.
何 この音 気持悪い。
That sound gives me the creeps.
早くこのエリアから抜け出さなきゃ。
We should high tail it out of here.
ええ 警戒しながら進みますよ。
Yeah, but let's proceed
with caution.
♪♪(琵琶)
《ホウイチ : 法力 影法師》
Power of Dharma: Silhouette.
♪♪(琵琶)
(ミコシ)
テンポが 変わった。 急ぎましょう。
The tempo's changed.
Let's hurry.
(マツリ)そうね。
Yes.
♪♪(琵琶)
何！
えっ 影が。
What is this?
Huh?! The shadows...!
なんだ コイツら。
What are these things?
(ミコシ)うわ～っ！
(ユカタ)キャーッ！
♪♪(琵琶)
砂分身！
Sand Clone!
我愛羅様 これは？
Lord Gaara, what's going on?!
コイツらの狙いは 俺だ。
Their target is me.
お前たちが関わり合う必要はない。
There's no need for you
to get involved.
風影様が危ないとき戦うのは→
It's our duty as Sand Shinobi to fight
when our Kazekage is threatened!
砂隠れの忍としての義務です。
お前たちは二次試験に戻れ。
Return to the Second Exam.
それが砂隠れの忍としての義務だ。
That is your duty as Sand Shinobi!
《ホウイチ : 法力封印術！
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
仙除離吸！》
Sen no Rikyu!
伏せろ！
Get down!
ううっ…。
《力が 抜けていく…》
I'm losing... my power...
(マツリ)鎖を。
The chain!
鎖を引き抜くのよ！
Let's pull out the chain!
(ユカタ/ミコシ)ああ！
– R-Right!
(マツリたち)うわっ！
行け ここは俺ひとりで。
Go! I can do this alone...
でも…。
風影として命令する。
But...
I order you as the Kazekage
to withdraw immediately!
速やかに
お前たちは ここから離脱。
このことは他言無用。 いいな？
And not a word of this
to anyone, understood?
(ユカタ)ねぇ どうすればいいの？
W-What'll we do?
(ミコシ)そんなこと
俺にだってわからない。
How should I know?!
中央塔の本部へ。
助っ人を呼ぶの。
Let's go to the central tower
and get help!
でも 風影様は他言無用って。
But... Lord Kazekage swore us
to secrecy!
バカ！ お命が危ないのよ！
You fool! His life is in danger!
《抵抗も そこまでだ。
Resistance is useless.
This is the sealing jutsu passed on
to me by Priest Bunpuku!
分福様から受け継ぎし封印術。
これより
守鶴を我愛羅から引き抜く！》
Now, I can extract Shukaku
from Gaara.
ううっ…。
ユカタ 大丈夫か？
Yukata! Are you all right?
I-I... can't move anymore.
もうダメ… 動けない。
マツリ ユカタは動けそうにない。
どうする？
Matsuri! Yukata can't go on!
What do we do?
ミコシ ユカタのことは頼む。
Mikoshi, take care of Yukata!
私が我愛羅様のことを
本部にお知らせしてくる。
I'm going to inform headquarters
about Lord Gaara!
しかし１人で…。
お願い 私は行く。
But, by yourself?!
Watch Yukata! I'm going!
マツリ…。
Matsuri...
♪♪(フウ)「100人の友ができるかな」
I wonder if I'm going to make
a hundred friends...?
(ヨウロウ)ったく あの気まぐれが！
She is so impulsive!
(ケゴン)中忍試験を放棄して
どうするつもりだ？
She's abandoning the Chunin Exams?
What is she up to?!
♪♪(琵琶)
ふぅ～。
やっと追いついた。
Fuu...
We finally caught up...
(ケゴン/ヨウロウ)うわっ！
おい どこへ行くんだ フウ！
Where are you going, Fuu?!
二次試験に戻るのか？
Are you going back
for the Second Exam?
うぅ… やはり読めない。
I just can't figure her out!
あっ！
待て！
– Hey!
– Wait!
せっかくできた同胞が
危ない目にあってるっす！
The friend I just made
is in trouble!
同胞？
Friend?
お前まさか 助けに行くつもりか？
もちろんっす。
Don't tell me
you're going to help?!
Of course!
戻ってこい フウ！
Come back, Fuu!
クソーッ！
こうなったら二次試験は諦める。
Damn it!
Never mind
the Second Exam already!
アイツを無事に連れ戻せれば
それでいい。
We just have to
get her back safely!
あぁ…。
Y-Yeah...
ええい ここを通せ！
Hey! Let us pass!
火影から 風影様への書状である。
We have a letter for Lord Kazekage
from Lady Hokage!
預かる！
そうはいかんのだ！
We'll take it!
That won't do!
風影様に 直接お渡しする！
だから それはできんのだ。
We must deliver it
directly to Lord Kazekage.
I explained that's not possible!
こちらにはおられぬ。
He's not here!
こちらにも！
Not here either!
様子が変ね。
ああ。
Something's up.
Yeah... The Kazekage isn't here.
風影様は ここにはいない…。
なんとな！
What in the world?!
The Kazekage....?
風影が… うぅ…。
アハハハ…。
♪♪(琵琶)
うっ この鎖は…
チャクラが吸い取られていく…。
This chain...
is extracting my chakra...
《あれは!?
間違いない 尾獣チャクラ。
That's...!
There's no mistake.
That's Tailed Beast chakra!
このままじゃ
尾獣を抜かれて死んじゃうっす》
If left alone, his Tailed Beast
will be extracted... and he'll die!
《フウ…》
Fuu!
来るな！
お前には関係ないことだ！
Stay away!
This has nothing to do with you.
アッシにも関係あるっす！
It does have something
to do with me!
わかってるっしょ？
アッシのこと。
You know about me... don't you?
Yes. You're a Jinchuriki too.
ああ お前も人柱力だな。
だから
アンタの苦しみはわかるっすよ。
That's why I can
feel your pain too.
苦しみを分かち合えるのが
友だって教えてくれたっす。
And you taught me that friends
understand each other's pain.
やめろ！
Stop it...!
うっ！
あぁ…。
力が吸い取られるっす。
It's sucking out my power...
大丈夫か!?
Are you all right?!
《もう１人いたのか。
So there's another one...
おもしろい。 分福様でも→
How interesting...
Not even Lord Bunpuku ever
sealed two Tailed Beasts at once.
尾獣２体を一気に
封印したことはあるまい。
法力封印の威力を
試すには絶好の機会》
This is the perfect opportunity to test
the power of the Dharma Seal.
♪♪(琵琶)
フウ 気をつけろ！
Fuu! Be careful!
なっ!?
ああっ！
フウ！
Fuu!
くっ… ごめん。
アッシ 失敗したみたいっす。
I-I'm sorry...
I think I failed...
《法力 仙除離吸》
Dharma Sealing Jutsu:
Sen no Rikyu!
♪♪(琵琶)
ああっ！
ゴホッ ゴホッ！
砂嵐が もう少し続いていたら→
If the sandstorm continued
any longer,
ここが私たちの
お墓になってたわよ。
this would have
become our grave.
(リー)何が起こるか
わからないのが魔の砂漠です！
You never know
what will happen next.
That's the Demon Desert!
さっさと二次試験通過と
いきましょう！
Let's get this Second Exam
over with.
そうね 中央塔は ここから
そう遠くないはずだし。
Right! The central tower
isn't far from here.
さあ レッツゴーです！
All right! Let's go!
What's the matter?
どうかしましたか？
何か忘れ物？
Did you forget something?
ああ 中央塔に行く前に
しなければならないことがある。
Yeah...
There's something we need to do
before we head for the central tower.
そうですね 僕にも決着を
つけたい相手がいました。
Yes.
There's someone I want
to settle things with too.
そういう方がいるんですね！
Do you have someone
like that too?
いや そういうことではない。
No, it's nothing like that.
それに何か問題が？
Is there something
the matter with them?
ちゃんと２本揃ってるし。
We have two scrolls.
実は…。
Actually...
– What?!
(リー/テンテン)え～っ!?
２本とも天の書だ。
なぜなんです!?
They're both "Heaven" scrolls.
How could you?!
なぜ そんな大事なことを
今まで秘密にしていたんですか!?
Why did you keep something
so important a secret?!
別に秘密にしていたわけではない。
I didn't intend to
keep it a secret.
ただ いろいろあって
話すチャンスがなかっただけだ。
It's just that things happened and
I didn't have a chance to tell you.
それって
何の言い訳にもなってないし。
That's a really bad excuse...
こうなったら 気をとりなおして→
Well, we'll just have to recoup
and obtain an "Earth" scroll somehow.
地の書の巻き物を
手に入れるしかありませんね。
ん？
Byakugan!
白眼！
あっちだ。
Over that way!
ちょっと待ってください！
ったくもう！
Please wait!
Oh, come on!
えっ え～!? あんな
疲れきったような人から→
H-Hey! You're going to take
a scroll from someone
who's ready to drop
from exhaustion?!
巻き物を奪うつもりですか？
そんな卑怯者がやるようなことは
断じてできません！
We can't do something
so cowardly!
早とちりするな！
Don't jump to conclusions!
We can't ignore someone
in distress.
行き倒れを
放ってはおけないだろう。
That's right!
そうね！ 大体 ネジが そんな
酷いことするわけないでしょ。
Neji would never stoop
to such a dirty trick.
アハハ… 当然 そんなふうには
思っていませんが。
Of course not! The thought
never crossed my mind...
(ネジ)どうした？ 何かあったのか？
Did something happen?
風影様が… 我愛羅様が
何者かに襲われているんです。
It's Lord Kazekage!
Someone is attacking Lord Gaara!
我愛羅が？
Gaara?!
《あと少しだ》
Just a little longer.
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
No one will come to help us.
今回 オープニングを飾るのは
小林幸子さんです。
Negative thoughts aren't good!
No matter how long
we wait,
モクハチは もとより→
reinforcements from
the Sand won't come!
テレビでは初めて披露する
特別のステージです。
Again with those
negative thoughts!
Would you still say that
if you knew
that the one attacking us
is from the Sand?
Are you serious?!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Neji's Judgment"
But I'm sure someone
will come to save us!